<Publish>
	<!--Id must be set in order to update existed mod. it is not required for publishing mod for the first time-->
	<ModId Value=""/>
	<!--Name of the mod to display to players-->
	<DisplayName Value="Fast Boarding"/>
	<!--Short description of the mod-->
	<ShortDescription Value="Limits total time transit waits at stops; Late passengers stop preventing transit from leaving, causing endless boarding."/>
	<!--Long description of the mod. Single line or multi line. Supports minimal markdown subset-->
	<!--LongDescription Value="This is a long description" /-->
	<LongDescription>
## Fast Boarding [Beta]

Faster public transit boarding
- Increase transit usage, reduce blocked stops, reduce private car demand indirectly.
- The larger your city, the more this mod will help.
- Instead of replacing the transport system files, this build focuses on two behaviors:

- **Prefab stop tuning** for bus, tram, train, subway, ship, ferries, and air transit
- **Optional Let Vehicles Leave** so tardy citizens can miss a vehicle instead of holding it forever.

### What the sliders do

Tune boarding speeds for:

- Bus, Rail (train, tram, subway), Water (ship, ferry), Air
- Higher values shorten dwell time by increasing stop loading speed and adjusting the boarding-time estimate used by the game.
- ✅ When **Let Vehicles Leave** is enabled, late passengers who are *still not ready* after *departure time* can be dropped from that vehicle's boarding process.
- The goal is simple: let the vehicle leave instead of waiting on passengers who are late, possibly far away. The game then naturally reassigns them.

### Status report included
- After the city runs a bit, check the Options menu to see current status.
- *Skipped* number shows how many late passengers have been skipped so the transit can leave on time.
- This is a snapshot of right-now; if the skip number stays at "0" for a long time, make sure to enable the checkbox ✅.
- For more detailed stats, use the [Stats to Log] button.
- Example usage: Worst stop shows over 10 minutes, check it for traffic, bad placement, not enough vehicles, or replace the stop.
- This is a one-shot button that does not run in the city per-frame, so no performance impact.
- When investigating, I like to click the button every 30 min, then compare the report later; it also shows exactly where the worst stops are and more.

### Notes
- Compatibility: conflict will be with any mod that touches boarding behavior, like All-Aboard, so choose one or the other.
- This is intended to be a lighter, safer alternative than replacing the game's entire Transport system files.
- Group boarding is handled conservatively to avoid splitting groups across platform and vehicle.
- This mod works well with `Public Works Plus` to solve many transit issues.
- Save-game safe. Safe to remove anytime.
- No Harmony patches; lightweight design for low overhead and negligible performance impact.

### Support and feedback
If mods help you, give them a Like, it's easy way to show support for free mods :)
Feedback on: Github, Discord, etc., link icons on this page.

### Credits
- RiverMochi....mod author
- Inspiration and thanks to bcallender's All Aboard mod and Wayze's old InstantBoarding.
- yenyang.......for testing and code feedback
- Neco1996......for testing
- MayorCheeks...for testing



</LongDescription>
	<!--Thumbnail-->
	<Thumbnail Value="Properties/Thumbnail-Trainboard02.jpg"/>
	<!--Screenshot, can be set multiple times-->
	<Screenshot Value="Properties/image10-BoardingSpeed.jpg"/>
	<Screenshot Value="Properties/image20-Status.jpg"/>
	<!--Tag, can be set multiple times-->
	<Tag Value=""/>
	<!--Link to the forum post where the mod can be discussed-->
	<ForumLink Value=""/>
	<!--Version of the mod-->
	<ModVersion Value="1.0.1"/>
	<!--Recommended version of the base game to use the mod-->
	<GameVersion Value="1.5.*"/>
	<!--Dependency for the mod, can be set multiple times-->
	<Dependency Id=""/>
	<!--Change log for new version. Single line or multi line. Supports minimal markdown subset-->
	<ChangeLog>

</ChangeLog>
	<!--External link. supported types are discord, github, youtube, twitch, x, paypal, patreon, buymeacoffee, kofi, crowdin, gitlab-->
	<ExternalLink Type="github" Url="https://github.com/River-Mochi/FastBoarding"/>
	<ExternalLink Type="discord" Url="https://discord.gg/HTav7ARPs2"/>
</Publish>
