<Publish>
	<!--Id must be set in order to update existed mod. it is not required for publishing mod for the first time-->
	<ModId Value=""/>
	<!--Name of the mod to display to players-->
	<DisplayName Value="Faster Boarding"/>
	<!--Short description of the mod-->
	<ShortDescription Value="Limits total time transit waits at stops; tardy passengers can miss the vehicle instead of causing endless boarding."/>
	<!--Long description of the mod. Single line or multi line. Supports minimal markdown subset-->
	<!--LongDescription Value="This is a long description" /-->
	<LongDescription>
## Faster Boarding [Beta]

Safer, faster public transit boarding
- Increase transit usage, reduce blocked stops, reduce private car demand indirectly.
- The larger your city, the more this mod will help.
- Instead of replacing the transportAIsystems, this build focuses on two behaviors:

- **Prefab stop tuning** for bus, tram, train, subway, ship, ferries, and air transit
- **Optional late-boarder cancellation** so passengers can miss a vehicle instead of holding it forever.

### What the sliders do

Tune boarding speeds for:

- Bus, Rail (train, tram, subway), Water (ship, ferry), Air
- Higher values shorten dwell time by increasing stop loading speed and adjusting the boarding-time estimate used by the game.
- ✅ When **Let vehicle leave** is enabled, passengers who are Late (*not ready*) after *departure time* can be dropped from that vehicle's boarding process.
- The goal is for the vehicle to leave and not have to wait for on the way passengers. Then the game's vanilla methods can handle the rest of the passenger flow.

### Status report in Options menu
- After the city runs a bit, check the options menu to see status for the mod
- Skipped number shows the mod is working and how many late passengers have been skipped so that the transit can leave on time.
- If the number is "0", ensure the checkbox is enabled. This is also a snapshot of RIGHT NOW.
- I like to see the worst stop is under 3 min, if it's more, I inspect.
- For More detailed organized stats, use the [Stats to Log] button.
- I like to click the button every 30 min, then compare the report later for changes, it also shows you exactly where your worst stops are.

### Notes
- Compatibility: 'All Aboard' will conflict with this mod since it also modifies boarding behavior, so choose one or the other.
- This is intended to be a lighter alternative than replacing the vanilla transport AI systems.
- Group boarding is handled conservatively to avoid splitting groups across platform and vehicle.
- Safe to remove anytime.
- No Harmony patches; lightweight design as to not cause performance issues


### Credits
- RiverMochi (mod author)
- Inspiration and thanks to bcallender's All Aboard mod.

</LongDescription>
	<!--Thumbnail-->
	<Thumbnail Value="Properties/Thumbnail.png"/>
	<!--Screenshot, can be set multiple times-->
	<Screenshot Value="Properties/unbunched-trains.png"/>
	<Screenshot Value="Properties/before-mod.png"/>
	<Screenshot Value="Properties/after-mod.png"/>
	<!--Tag, can be set multiple times-->
	<Tag Value=""/>
	<!--Link to the forum post where the mod can be discussed-->
	<ForumLink Value=""/>
	<!--Version of the mod-->
	<ModVersion Value="1.0.1"/>
	<!--Recommended version of the base game to use the mod-->
	<GameVersion Value="1.5.*"/>
	<!--Dependency for the mod, can be set multiple times-->
	<Dependency Id=""/>
	<!--Change log for new version. Single line or multi line. Supports minimal markdown subset-->
	<ChangeLog>

</ChangeLog>
	<!--External link. supported types are discord, github, youtube, twitch, x, paypal, patreon, buymeacoffee, kofi, crowdin, gitlab-->
	<ExternalLink Type="github" Url="https://github.com/River-Mochi/FastBoarding"/>
	<ExternalLink Type="discord" Url="https://discord.gg/HTav7ARPs2"/>
</Publish>
