<Publish>
	<!--Id must be set in order to update existed mod. it is not required for publishing mod for the first time-->
	<ModId Value="141997"/>
	<!--Name of the mod to display to players-->
	<DisplayName Value="Fast Boarding"/>
	<!--Short description of the mod-->
	<ShortDescription Value="Faster Transit Boarding; Late solo passengers stop holding up vehicles, and bus/tram cims may start running earlier to catch their ride. "/>
	<!--Long description of the mod. Single line or multi line. Supports minimal markdown subset-->
	<!--LongDescription Value="This is a long description" /-->
	<LongDescription>
## Faster public transit boarding

Still useful with patch 1.5.7-1.5.8.

The game now has a fallback for stuck transit and releases them if it's ~10 minutes past scheduled departure time.
Fast Boarding helps before that by making boarding faster and reducing late-passenger delays to keep things smooth and on time.

- Improve traffic, increase transit usage, reduce bunching of vehicles.
- The larger your city, the more this mod will help.
- ✅ Speeds up public transit boarding/loading with simple sliders.
- ✅ Lets late solo cims miss a vehicle (if it's after departure time) so everyone else is not held up.
- ✅ Late cims can also start running sooner so they have a chance to catch their ride (bus + tram currently).
- ✅ Adds compact Status info in Options menu and a detailed [Stats to Log] report.

### Skip Late Passengers
- ✅ When **Skip Late Passengers** is enabled, late solo cims who are still **not ready** even after **departure time** can miss that vehicle instead of making everyone wait.
- The cim is not deleted. The game can naturally reassign them.
- Groups/families traveling together are left to vanilla methods so they are not split up.

### Cims Run sooner: Bus + Tram

- ✅ When **Cims Run Sooner** is ON, the assigned but late passengers can start running a little sooner.
- Vanilla starts cims running at departure time, which can be too late to help if they are not already near the stop.
- Like real life, people start running from a block away, not just at the stop.
- It reduces how many cims need to be reassigned later. Currently only works for bus/trams; does not force boarding or teleport citizens.


### Status report included
After the city runs a bit, check the Options menu to see current status.
- *Skipped* shows how many late solo passengers have been skipped today (so they do not hold up transit).
- Example usage: Worst stop shows 10+ minutes, check it for traffic, bad placement, not enough vehicles, or replace the stop.
- This is a one-shot button that does not run in the city per-frame, so no real performance impact.
- When checking things, I like to click the Stats button every ~20+ min, then compare the report later to see where the worst stops are and more (Scene Explorer mod helps locate the Entity ID numbers).
- Use [Stats to Log] button for more detailed snapshot data than what is shown in Options menu.

### Notes
- Important compatibility: conflicts possible with mods that change boarding, like All-Aboard, so Only Choose One.
Some players report no issues with Smart Transportation + Fast boarding together.
- Mod is intended to be a lighter, safer alternative than replacing the game's transport system files approach.
- This mod works nicely with `Public Works Plus` to solve many transit issues.
- Group boarding is left to normal vanilla handling to avoid splitting groups (they are few compared to the many single travelers).
- Save-game safe. Safe to remove anytime.
- No Harmony patches; lightweight design for low overhead.
- Supports 11 languages.

### Support and feedback
- If mods make the game better, give it a Like. It's an easy way to show support for free mods :)
- Feedback on: Github, Discord, etc., link icons on this page.

### Credits
- River-Mochi_____mod author
- Inspiration and thanks to bcallender's All Aboard mod and Wayze's old InstantBoarding.
- yenyang_________testing and code feedback
- Neco1996________testing
- MayorCheeks_____testing
- gagaxm__________testing
- Empiiey_________testing
- elGaucho87______thumbnail straightener

If you got this far, congrats, say hi, there is a senryu poem I wrote just for you in images. Click Like button, it's hard, I know, and so tiny.

tags: boarding time, bus stop, slow transit, debunching, unbunching

</LongDescription>
	<!--Thumbnail-->
	<Thumbnail Value="Properties/Thumbnail-Boarding.jpg"/>
	<!--Screenshot, can be set multiple times-->
	<Screenshot Value="Properties/image10-BoardingSpeed.jpg"/>
	<Screenshot Value="Properties/image30-Status.jpg"/>
    <Screenshot Value="Properties/image40-11Languages.jpg"/>
    <Screenshot Value="Properties/image60-senryu-FastBoarding.jpg"/>

	<!--Tag, can be set multiple times-->
	<Tag Value=""/>
	<!--Link to the forum post where the mod can be discussed-->
	<ForumLink Value="https://forum.paradoxplaza.com/forum/threads/fast-boarding.1918695/"/>
	<!--Version of the mod-->
	<ModVersion Value="1.1.0"/>
	<!--Recommended version of the base game to use the mod-->
	<GameVersion Value="1.5.*"/>
	<!--Dependency for the mod, can be set multiple times-->
	<Dependency Id=""/>
	<!--Change log for new version. Single line or multi line. Supports minimal markdown subset-->
	<ChangeLog>
- Add Cims Run Sooner: Bus + Tram option.
- Add Italian and Polish translations.
- Update all locale files to align with English.
- Set 3x as default, and 5x as maximum boarding-speed scaler.
- Improve status report.
- Improve Stats to Log report with clearer tester hints, worst stops, entity IDs, and late-group notes.
- Improve verbose diagnostic logging for testers.
</ChangeLog>
	<!--External link. supported types are discord, github, youtube, twitch, x, paypal, patreon, buymeacoffee, kofi, crowdin, gitlab-->
	<ExternalLink Type="github" Url="https://github.com/River-Mochi/FastBoarding"/>
	<ExternalLink Type="discord" Url="https://discord.gg/HTav7ARPs2"/>
</Publish>
