<Publish>
	<!--Id must be set in order to update existed mod. it is not required for publishing mod for the first time-->
	<ModId Value="141997"/>
	<!--Name of the mod to display to players-->
	<DisplayName Value="Fast Boarding"/>
	<!--Short description of the mod-->
	<ShortDescription Value="Improves traffic with faster Transit Boarding + Loading; optional Late solo passengers stop holding up transit."/>
	<!--Long description of the mod. Single line or multi line. Supports minimal markdown subset-->
	<!--LongDescription Value="This is a long description" /-->
	<LongDescription>
        ## Faster public transit boarding

        YES - this mod still useful with patch (1.5.7-1.5.8). The game patch added a fallback so stuck transit can move after ~10 minutes.

        Fast Boarding helps before that point by with improved boarding/loading speeds and ability to reduce late passengers that prevent transit from leaving stops.

        - Improve traffic, increase transit usage, reduce bunching of transit vehicles, reduce car demand indirectly.
        - The larger your city, the more this mod will help.

        - This build focuses on two behaviors:
        - **Adjustable stop tuning** for all transit, not just buses and trains. You choose the speed.
        - **Skip Late Passengers** (optional [x]) so tardy citizens can just miss a vehicle instead of holding it up (happens in vanilla now, frequently).
        - See **Notes** section for incompatible mods.

        Tune boarding speeds for:

        - Bus, Rail (train, tram, subway), Water (ship, ferry), Air
        - Higher values shorten dwell by increasing loading speed at the stop and adjusting the boarding-time estimate used by the game.
        - ✅ When **Skip Late Passengers** is enabled, late passengers who are *still not ready* after *departure time* can miss that vehicle instead of holding it up.
        - Simple Goal: don't wait on passengers who are still late or far away. The game then naturally reassigns them.

        ### Bonus Status report included
        - After the city runs a bit, check the Options menu to see current status.
        - *Skipped* number shows how many late solo passengers have been skipped today to not hold up transit.
        - Use [Stats to Log] button for more detailed data than what is in Options menu.
        - Example usage: Worst stop shows 10+ minutes, check it for traffic, bad placement, not enough vehicles, or replace the stop.
        - This is a one-shot button that does not run in the city per-frame, so no performance impact.
        - When checking things, I like to click the Stats button every ~20-30 min, then compare the report later to see where the worst stops are and more (Scene Explorer mod can help with this too).
        - Each time you enter the menu, it does a 1-time scan of current city info (never while running city).


        ### Notes
        - Important compatibility: conflicts possible with mods that change boarding behavior, like All-Aboard, so Only choose One.
        Some players report no issues with Smart Transportation + Fast boarding together.
        - This mod is intended to be a lighter, safer alternative than replacing the game's Transport system files approach.
        - This mod works nicely with `Public Works Plus` to solve many transit issues.
        - Group boarding is left to normal vanilla handling to avoid splitting groups (they are few compared to the many single travelers).
        - Save-game safe. Safe to remove anytime.
        - No Harmony patches; lightweight design for low overhead and negligible performance impact.

        ### Support and feedback
        - If mods make the game better, give it a Like. It's an easy way to show support for free mods :)
        - Feedback on: Github, Discord, etc., link icons on this page.

        ### Credits
        - River-Mochi_____mod author
        - Inspiration and thanks to bcallender's All Aboard mod and Wayze's old InstantBoarding.
        - yenyang_________testing and code feedback
        - Neco1996________testing
        - MayorCheeks_____testing
        - elGaucho87______thumbnail straightening

        If you got this far, congrats, say hi, there is a senryu poem I wrote just for you in images. click Like button, it's hard, I know, and so tiny.

        tags: boarding time, bus stop, slow transit, debunching, unbunching

    </LongDescription>
	<!--Thumbnail-->
	<Thumbnail Value="Properties/Thumbnail-Boarding.jpg"/>
	<!--Screenshot, can be set multiple times-->
	<Screenshot Value="Properties/image10-BoardingSpeed.jpg"/>
	<Screenshot Value="Properties/image30-Status.jpg"/>
    <Screenshot Value="Properties/image40-senryu-FastBoarding.jpg"/>

	<!--Tag, can be set multiple times-->
	<Tag Value=""/>
	<!--Link to the forum post where the mod can be discussed-->
	<ForumLink Value="https://forum.paradoxplaza.com/forum/threads/fast-boarding.1918695/"/>
	<!--Version of the mod-->
	<ModVersion Value="1.0.4"/>
	<!--Recommended version of the base game to use the mod-->
	<GameVersion Value="1.5.*"/>
	<!--Dependency for the mod, can be set multiple times-->
	<Dependency Id=""/>
	<!--Change log for new version. Single line or multi line. Supports minimal markdown subset-->
	<ChangeLog>
- add Italian and Polish
- update all locale files to align with English
- internal add more info for stats report + verbose logging

</ChangeLog>
	<!--External link. supported types are discord, github, youtube, twitch, x, paypal, patreon, buymeacoffee, kofi, crowdin, gitlab-->
	<ExternalLink Type="github" Url="https://github.com/River-Mochi/FastBoarding"/>
	<ExternalLink Type="discord" Url="https://discord.gg/HTav7ARPs2"/>
</Publish>
